YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series IV. Constituent Groups
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. CONSTITUENT GROUPS
  - Subseries A. Employed Women
    - Business and Professional Women
      - Council
        - National Council
          - Questionnaire to locals re role and function of Council, fall 1947 (Box 485, Folder 5)
        - Area/Regional Councils
          - Central, 1932-45 (Box 485, Folder 6)
          - East Central (eastern part of Central Area-aka Forest Beach), 1938-50 (Box 485, Folder 7-8)
          - East Central (central part of Eastern Area), 1939-46 (Box 485, Folder 9)
          - Eastern
            - General, 1926-39 (Box 485, Folder 10)
            - Minutes, 1938-50 (Box 485, Folder 11-12)
          - Northwest
            - General, 1938-47, n.d. (Box 485, Folder 13)
          - Southern
            - General, 1940-47 (Box 485, Folder 13)
            - Minutes
              - 1937-42 (Box 485, Folder 13)
              - 1943-50 (Box 486, Folder 1)
          - Southwest
            - General, 1939-42 (Box 486, Folder 2)
            - Minutes, 1939-49 (Box 486, Folder 3-4)
          - West Central: minutes, 1942-50 (Box 486, Folder 5-6)
          - Western
            - General, 1939-43 (Box 486, Folder 7)
      - Nation-wide/World-wide Observance, 1933-34, 1939, 1942-49 (Box 486, Folder 8-17)
      - National Assembly
        - General, 1930-44 (Box 486, Folder 18)
        - Commissions/Projects/Emphases
          - General, 1925-32 (Box 486, Folder 19)
          - 1929-31: Vocational Adjustment (Box 486, Folder 20)
          - 1932-34
            - Clerical Organization (Box 486, Folder 21)
            - Economics (Box 487, Folder 1)
            - Increased Development of Spiritual Resources (Box 487, Folder 2)
            - Increased Participation in the Association (Box 487, Folder 3)
            - Increased Skill in Citizenship (Box 487, Folder 4)
            - Progression of the Individual Girl (Box 487, Folder 5)
          - 1936-38
            - General (Box 487, Folder 6)
            - Cooperative Movements (Box 487, Folder 7)
            - Freedom of Speech (Box 487, Folder 8)
            - Minority Groups (Box 487, Folder 9)
            - Participation and Freedom of Action (Box 487, Folder 10)
            - Religion (Box 487, Folder 11)
            - Workers' Education (Box 487, Folder 12)
            - Youth Movement (Box 487, Folder 13)
          - 1938-40: Economic Security (Box 487, Folder 14)
          - 1944-48 (Box 487, Folder 15)
      - Organizations
        - Jewish Welfare Board/Young Women's Hebrew Association/YWCA: business girls discussion group, 1927-28 (Box 487, Folder 16)
        - National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs
          - General and history, 1919-41, n.d. (Box 487, Folder 17)
          - Constitution and by-laws, 1919, n.d. (Box 487, Folder 18)
          - Formation
            - Conference of Business and Professional Women with the National Board, May 1918 (Box 487, Folder 19)
            - B and P Women's Conference of the Northeast and East Central Fields of the YWCA, May 1919 (Box 487, Folder 20)
            - National Business Women's Committee, 1918-19 (Box 487, Folder 21)
          - Conventions
            - First, St. Louis, Jul 1919
              - General (Box 487, Folder 22)
              - Program (Box 488, Folder 1)
              - Proceedings (Box 488, Folder 2-7)
            - Second, St. Paul, Jul 1920 (Box 488, Folder 8)
          - Directory, 1920-21 (Box 488, Folder 9)
      - Project: Business Office Culture
        - Proposal to U.S. Dept of Labor and progress report, 1968 (Box 488, Folder 10)
        - Final report, Sep 1969 (Box 488, Folder 11)
      - Publications
        - General, 1921-44, n.d. (Box 488, Folder 12)
        - As Told By Business Girls: Problems in Personal Adjustment by Margaret S. Quayle, TWP, 1932 (Box 488, Folder 13)
        - The Business Girl Looks at the Negro World by Frances Harriet Williams, TWP 1937 (Box 488, Folder 14)
        - Business and Professional Committee, 1935-40 (Box 489, Folder 1)
        - Clerical workers, 1928-38 (Box 489, Folder 2)
        - Dos and Don'ts for Business Women by Jean Rich (Helen Frances Thompson), TWP 1922 (Box 489, Folder 3)
        - Jobs and Marriage? by Grace Coyle, TWP 1928 (Box 489, Folder 4)
        - Program, 1919-36 (Box 489, Folder 5)
        - Religion, 1920-42 (Box 489, Folder 6-7)
        - The Ways of a Business Woman by Marion Lela Norris, 1924 (Box 489, Folder 8)
        - Serials
          - Exchange Sheet...
            - Feb 1923-1924 (Box 489, Folder 9-10)
            - 1925-Jun 1928 (Box 490, Folder 1-5)
          - Program Exchange
            - Jan 1933-1935 (Box 490, Folder 6-11)
            - 1936-Mar 1939 (Box 491, Folder 1-8)
          - The Business and Professional News and Notes
            - Sep 1939-Feb 1941 (Box 491, Folder 9-11)
            - May 1941-Jul 1944 (Box 492, Folder 1-8)
      - Studies
        - "From Pay Day to Pay Day" A study conducted during 1931-32 by Elsie D. Harper, 1934 (Box 492, Folder 9)
        - "Leisure-Time Interests and Activities of Business Girls," a research study conducted during 1931-33 by Janet Fowler Nelson (Box 492, Folder 10)
    - Household Employment
      - General and History
        - General, 1870-46, n.d. (Box 493, Folder 1-4)
        - Bibliographies, 1930-39, n.d. (Box 493, Folder 5)
        - Employment Standards, 1930-40, n.d. (Box 493, Folder 6)
        - Legislation, 1932-40, n.d. (Box 493, Folder 7-8)
        - "Negro," 1923-36 (Box 493, Folder 9)
        - Placement, 1928-39 (Box 493, Folder 10)
        - Unionization, 1933-38, n.d. (Box 493, Folder 11)
        - Voluntary Employer-Employee Agreement, 1930-39, n.d. (Box 493, Folder 12)
      - Committees
        - Commission on Household Employment: reports, 1915-ca. 1917, n.d. (Box 493, Folder 13)
        - Industrial Committee: reports by E. Beatrice Stearns, Special Worker for Household Employment, 1919-20 (Box 493, Folder 14)
        - Sub-Committee on Household Employment of the Public Affairs Committee
          - General, 1930-38 (Box 493, Folder 15)
          - Symposium co-sponsored with the Federal Council of Churches, "Fair and Clear in the Home," 1936-39 (Box 493, Folder 16-17)
        - Sub-Committee on Household Employment of the Lab Division/Community Division, 1939-41 (Box 494, Folder 1)
        - Ad-hoc Committee on Household Employment, 1945 (Box 494, Folder 2)
        - Local associations files by state, 1932-40, n.d.
          - A - New Jersey (Box 494, Folder 3-23)
          - New York - Wisconsin (Box 495, Folder 1-16)
        - National Industrial Assembly and Industrial Conferences
          - General, 1926-38 (Box 495, Folder 17-18)
          - Household Employment Project, 1931-41 (Box 495, Folder 19-20)
        - Organizations
          - National Committee on Employer-Employee Relationships in the Home, 1928-33, n.d. (Box 496, Folder 1-2)
          - National Committee/Council on Household Employment, 1934-36 (Box 496, Folder 3)
        - Publications
          - General, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 496, Folder 4)
          - Concerns of Household Workers: Program with Household Workers in the YWCA by Jean Collier Brown, 1941 (Box 496, Folder 5)
        - Reference materials
          - General, 1911-40 (Box 497, Folder 1)
          - International
            - General, 1925-39 (Box 497, Folder 2)
            - World's YWCA, 1930-38 (Box 497, Folder 3)
          - Training Programs, 1934-40, n.d. (Box 497, Folder 4)
    - Industrial Work
      - General and History
        - General, 1908-80, n.d. (Box 498, Folder 1-2)
        - Thesis: "A Study of One Hundred Employed Girls and Women In Selected Factories on the North Side: Personal Data, Job Experience and Use of Free Time; Its Implications for Recruitment and Program" by Wilma Stringfellow, University of Pittsburgh School of Social Work, 1949 (Box 498, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence
          - General, 1906-49 (Box 498, Folder 4)
          - YWCA relations with employers, 1920-25 (Box 498, Folder 5)
        - Creeds, 1921-25, n.d. (Box 498, Folder 6)
        - Federation of Industrial and Extension Clubs, 1912-ca. 1919, n.d. (Box 498, Folder 7)
        - Local Clubs/Committees
          - General, 1910-45, n.d. (Box 498, Folder 8)
          - Illinois, Chicago, 1934 (Box 498, Folder 9)
          - Indiana, Indianapolis, 1933 (Box 498, Folder 10)
          - Massachusetts, Lawrence, 1943-44 (Box 498, Folder 11)
          - New York, Buffalo
            - General, 1924-48, n.d. (Box 498, Folder 12)
            - Industrial Department notebook, ca. 1948 (Box 498, Folder 13)
            - "A Study of Backgrounds of Industrial Women of Buffalo" by Eleanor Coit, 1923 (Box 498, Folder 14)
            - "Some Salient Facts Concerning Business and Industrial Girls of South Buffalo," 1924 (Box 498, Folder 15)
          - Pennsylvania: Manual for Counsellors of Industrial Groups, YWCA Council of Southwestern Pennsylvania, n.d. (Box 499, Folder 1)
        - Mill Villages work/Southern Cotton Mills
          - General, 1907-33, n.d. (Box 499, Folder 2)
          - Monaghan Mills YWCA, Greenville, South Carolina, 1906-10, [see also oversize scrapbook in Record Group 2] (Box 499, Folder 3)
          - Victor Manufacturing Company YWCA, Greer, South Carolina, 1908-09 (Box 499, Folder 4)
        - Policy
          - General, 1908-80, n.d. (Box 499, Folder 5)
          - Clippings, 1920-21 (Box 499, Folder 6)
          - Industrial Legislation, 1915-33, n.d. (Box 499, Folder 7)
        - Reference materials, 1910-39, n.d. (Box 499, Folder 8-9)
        - Secretaries Job Analysis, 1919-30 (Box 499, Folder 10)
        - "Southern situation," 1925-31 (Box 499, Folder 11-14)
        - Staff meetings, 1944-46 (Box 500, Folder 1-3)
        - Strikes, Paterson and Passaic, 1919, 1926-27 (Box 500, Folder 4)
        - Workers' Education, 1925-40, n.d. (Box 500, Folder 5)
        - World War II, 1939-44 (Box 500, Folder 6)
      - Committees
        - General, 1929-31 (Box 500, Folder 7)
        - Industrial Sub-Committee of the City Committee: minutes, 1914-16 (Box 500, Folder 8)
        - Industrial Committee: minutes
          - 1918-29 (Box 500, Folder 9-22)
          - 1930-31 (Box 501, Folder 1-2)
        - Industrial Sub-Committee (Leadership Division/Community YWCAs Division)
          - Minutes, 1935-49 (Box 501, Folder 3-7)
          - Hearing: Women workers and war production, Apr 1942 (Box 501, Folder 8)
        - National Industrial Research/Inquiry Commission
          - General, 1924-28 (Box 501, Folder 9)
          - Correspondence course on research methods, 1927 (Box 501, Folder 10)
        - World Fellowship and Industry, 1925-30 (Box 501, Folder 11)
      - Conferences
        - General, 1928-30, n.d. (Box 501, Folder 12)
        - National
          - 1918-19 (Box 501, Folder 13-14)
          - For Staff Working with Industrial Constituency, 1947
            - General, 1946-47 (Box 501, Folder 15)
            - Reference materials, 1946-47 (Box 501, Folder 16)
        - Secretaries'
          - 1916-20 (Box 501, Folder 17)
          - 1921-33 (Box 502, Folder 1-3)
        - Summer
          - General, 1920-48, n.d. (Box 502, Folder 4)
          - Altamont (NY and NJ), 1921-22 (Box 502, Folder 5-6)
          - Central Area/Region
            - Dewey Lake, 1922, 1924 (Box 502, Folder 7-8)
            - Forest Beach, 1923 (Box 502, Folder 9)
            - Winona Lake, 1923 (Box 502, Folder 10)
            - Camp Okoboji (Milford, IA), 1923-24, 1927 (Box 502, Folder 11-13)
            - Camp Gray (Saugatuck, MI), 1928-37 (Box 502, Folder 14-23)
            - Tower Hill Camp (Sawyer, MI)
              - 1938-41 (Box 502, Folder 24-27)
              - 1942 (Box 503, Folder 1)
          - East Central Area/Region (central part of eastern region)
            - Nepahwin (Canton, PA), 1922-25 (Box 503, Folder 2-5)
            - Camp Caledon (PA), 1926 (Box 503, Folder 6)
            - Camp Pawatinika (Annapolis, MD), 1927 (Box 503, Folder 7)
            - Doubling Gap, PA, 1928 (Box 503, Folder 8)
            - Camp Whelen (High Point, NJ), 1929-30 (Box 503, Folder 9-10)
          - East Central Area/Region (central part of eastern region)
            - Forest Beach Camp (New Buffalo, MI), 1943-44, 1946-50 (Box 503, Folder 11-17)
          - Eastern Area/Region
            - Silver Bay (Lake George, NY), 1919 (Box 503, Folder 18)
            - Makonikey (MA), 1920 (Box 503, Folder 19)
            - Prospect (Central Valley, NY), 1925-27 (Box 503, Folder 20-21)
            - Summit Lake (Central Valley, NY)
              - 1924, 1928-33 (Box 503, Folder 22-28)
              - 1935-42 (Box 504, Folder 1-9)
          - Southern Area/Region
            - Blue Ridge, 1918 (Box 504, Folder 10)
            - French Broad Camp, 1921 (Box 504, Folder 11)
            - Lake Junaluska (NC), 1922-23, 1926 (Box 504, Folder 12-14)
            - Camp Greystone (Tuxedo, NC), 1927-28 (Box 504, Folder 15-16)
            - Camp Merrie-Woode (Sapphire, NC)
              - 1929-41 (Box 505, Folder 1-13)
              - 1942-43 (Box 506, Folder 1-2)
            - Camp Highland Lake (Hendersonville, NC), 1946-47 (Box 506, Folder 3)
            - Lincoln Academy (Kings Mountain, NC), 1947 (Box 506, Folder 4)
            - Camp Chelan (Sellersburg, IA), 1949-50 (Box 506, Folder 5-6)
        - Weekend/Mid-winter
          - General, 1933-46 (Box 506, Folder 7)
          - Miscellaneous, 1920-46 (Box 506, Folder 8)
          - California, 1936-40 (Box 506, Folder 9)
          - East Central (Nepawhin Area), 1925-46 (Box 506, Folder 10)
          - New England, northern, 1927-50 (Box 506, Folder 11)
          - New England, southern, 1927-42 (Box 506, Folder 12)
          - New York and New Jersey, 1927-41 (Box 506, Folder 13)
          - New York, up-state, 1928-50, n.d. (Box 506, Folder 14)
          - North Carolina,1939-43 (Box 506, Folder 15)
          - Northeast, 1922-32 (Box 506, Folder 16)
          - Pennsylvania, eastern, 1929-42 (Box 506, Folder 17)
          - Pennsylvania, western, 1928-40 (Box 506, Folder 18)
          - Tri-City/Tri-State (Baltimore, MD, Washington, DC, Richmond, VA), 1936, 1940 (Box 506, Folder 19)
          - West Virginia, 1929, 1939 (Box 506, Folder 20)
      - Council
        - General, 1908-1936 (Box 507, Folder 1)
        - Handbook, 1942 (Box 507, Folder 2)
        - Rosters, 1931-49 (Box 507, Folder 3)
        - Rules of procedure, 1941-49 (Box 507, Folder 4)
        - National
          - General, 1930-50 (Box 507, Folder 5)
          - Financial, 1938-49 (Box 507, Folder 6)
          - Meetings, 1931-49 (Box 507, Folder 7-9)
          - "National Council News," 1938-40 (Box 507, Folder 10-12)
          - "National Industrial Council News," 1941-47 (Box 507, Folder 13-15)
        - Area/Regional Councils
          - General, 1919, 1934 (Box 507)
          - Albert Lea (Iowa, Minnesota, Nebraska, N. and S. Dakota), 1915 (Box 507)
          - Camp Gray (Saugatuck, MI), 1928-39 (Box 507)
          - Central (Dewey Lake), 1916-21, 1939-42 (Box 508, Folder 1-4)
          - East Central (central portion of eastern region), 1935-36 (Box 508, Folder 5)
          - East Central (eastern portion of central region), 1942-49 (Box 508, Folder 6)
          - Eastern (Camp Nepawhin), 1915-21, 1928-30, 1932-36, 1939-48 (Box 508, Folder 7-13)
          - Northeastern (Altamont/Makonikey), 1915-20 (Box 508, Folder 14-16)
          - South Atlantic, 1920-21 (Box 508, Folder 17)
          - South Atlantic and South Central, 1919 (Box 508, Folder 18)
          - Southern, 1929-49 (Box 508, Folder 19-21)
          - Storm Lake (Iowa), 1916-17 (Box 508, Folder 22)
          - West Central (Okoboji), 1924-50 (Box 508, Folder 23)
      - National Assembly
        - General, 1924-49 (Box 508, Folder 24)
        - Record book
          - 1926 (1 of 4) (Box 508, Folder 25)
          - (2-4 of 4) 1926, 1928 (Box 509, Folder 1-7)
        - Resolutions, 1936 (Box 509, Folder 8)
        - Post-Assembly Bulletin, 1938, 1940 (Box 509, Folder 9-10)
      - Programs and Projects
        - General, 1912-46, n.d. (Box 509, Folder 11)
        - Consultation on Women Workers in Industry and Service Trades: report, 1956 (Box 509, Folder 12)
        - East Tennessee Project (extension of work in), 1929, n.d. (Box 509, Folder 13)
        - Florence Simms Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1924-41, n.d. (Box 509, Folder 14)
        - Industrial Women's Service Centers/Clubs, 1920-27, n.d. (Box 509, Folder 15)
        - National Industrial Progress Day, [see also oversize-scrapbook, 1945]
          - 1941 (Box 509, Folder 16)
          - 1942-49 (Box 510, Folder 1-8)
        - Pageantry and drama, 1931, 1949, n.d. (Box 510, Folder 9)
        - Recreation, 1946, n.d. (Box 510, Folder 10)
        - Textile Industry Writing Groups, 1931-32 (Box 510, Folder 11)
        - U-Day (Union Day), 1945-50 (Box 510, Folder 12)
        - Victory Program, 1942-44 (Box 510, Folder 13)
      - Publications
        - History, 1920, 1928 (Box 510, Folder 14)
        - General
          - 1914-20 (Box 510, Folder 15-16)
          - 1926-43 (Box 511, Folder 1)
        - Industrial Committee, 1916-42 (Box 511, Folder 2)
        - Department of Industrial Work Leaflets: No. 1. How to Begin-Organization; No. 2. The Industrial Club and Its Program; No. 3. The Federation-An Industrial Movement, by Ernestine Friedmann1918-21 (Box 511, Folder 3)
        - Industrial Work in the Young Women's Christian Association: 1. Principles and Policy and II. Program and Method, 1930 (Box 511, Folder 4)
        - Program materials, 1920-27 (Box 511, Folder 5)
        - Women in Industry in the Orient: A Source Book, 1926 (Box 511, Folder 6)
        - Bulletin to Industrial Secretaries of the YWCA
          - 1923-27 (Box 511, Folder 7-11)
          - 1928 (Box 512, Folder 1)
        - [Industrial] Program Exchange
          - Index to 1935-36 issues (Box 512, Folder 2)
          - 1933-38 (Box 512, Folder 3-12)
          - 1939-44 (Box 513, Folder 1-7)
      - Reports
        - Miscellaneous, 1915-46, n.d. (Box 513, Folder 8)
        - Biennial/Convention
          - 1913-14, 1915-20, 1924-25, 1926-27 (Box 513, Folder 9-11)
          - 1928-29, 1930-31, 1935-37, 1937-40, 1939-44 (Box 514, Folder 1-3)
        - Case Studies in Local Industrial Work from reports sent to the National Industrial Department, 1929-30 (Box 514, Folder 4-5)
        - Secretary
          - List, 1924, 1925, 1929 (Box 514, Folder 6)
          - Carner, Lucy P., 1924-31 (Box 514, Folder 7-10)
          - Coit, Eleanor G., 1926-28 (Box 514, Folder 11-12)
          - Copenhaver, Eleanor
            - 1923-26 (Box 514, Folder 13-14)
            - 1927-31 (Box 515, Folder 1-4)
          - Coyle, Grace, 1922-25 (Box 515, Folder 5-6)
          - Dieckmann, Annetta, 1922-28 (Box 515, Folder 7-8)
          - Duntze, Wilma, 1929-31 (Box 515, Folder 9)
          - Friedmann, Ernestine L., 1918-19 (Box 515, Folder 10)
          - Gifford, Helen W., 1929-36 (Box 515, Folder 11)
          - Grumman, Anne Sophia, 1919-20 (Box 515, Folder 12)
          - Harper, Elsie D., 1929-30 (Box 515, Folder 13)
          - Hubbard, Dorothy L., 1928-31 (Box 515, Folder 14-15)
          - Ireland, Imogene B., 1920-21 (Box 515, Folder 16)
          - Jackson, Mary E., 1918-21 (Box 515, Folder 17)
          - Johnston, Alma E., 1926-27 (Box 515, Folder 18)
          - Leonard, Louise, 1922-27 (Box 516, Folder 1-2)
          - Nims, Mrs., 1931 (Box 516, Folder 3)
          - Owers, Anna, 1921 (Box 516, Folder 4)
          - Perry, Mary B., 1927-31 (Box 516, Folder 5-6)
          - Simms, Florence, 1916-21 (Box 516, Folder 7)
          - Stearns, E. Beatrice, 1920 (Box 516, Folder 8)
          - Van Horn, Olive, 1921 (Box 516, Folder 9)
          - Wood, Margaret Wells, 1918, n.d. (Box 516, Folder 10)
          - Wood, Mildred L., 1930 (Box 516, Folder 11)
      - Studies
        - Industrial Surveys by Jeannette White, 1920 (Box 516, Folder 12)
        - Digest of replies to letters sent out to Associations in Industrial towns, Feb 1929 (Box 516, Folder 13)
        - "The Industrial Work of the YWCA"
          - Committee minutes and correspondence, 1935-37 (Box 516, Folder 14)
          - Instructions and blank forms, Oct 1935 (Box 516, Folder 15)
          - Preliminary report by Annabel Stewart, 1937 (Box 516, Folder 16-20)
          - Final report by Annabel Stewart, 1937 (Box 516, Folder 21)
          - "Report relating to the local industrial program of the YWCA," 1937 (Box 517, Folder 1)
          - "Tentative Conclusions and Recommendations," Jan 1937 (Box 517, Folder 2)
          - "Conclusions and Recommendations," Apr 1938 (Box 517, Folder 3)
          - Follow up, 1937-40, n.d. (Box 517, Folder 4-6)
        - International Wage and Budget Study, 1929 (Box 517, Folder 7)
        - "Married Women in Industry," questionnaire, 1926, 1929 (Box 517, Folder 8-9)
        - Practical Applications of Workers' Education, by Ethel M. Smith, 1927 (Box 517, Folder 10)
      - Training Courses
        - Miscellaneous, 1918-27 (Box 517, Folder 11)
        - "Administration of the Industrial Extension Department," 1918 (Box 517, Folder 12)
        - "The Christian Woman in Industry," 1919 (Box 517, Folder 13)
        - "Christianity and Industry," 1919 (Box 517, Folder 14)
        - "The Evolution of the Industrial Program of the YWCA," 1927 (Box 517, Folder 15)
        - "Group Behavior," n.d. (Box 517, Folder 16)
        - "Group Work," 1928 (Box 517, Folder 17)
        - "Industrial Technique," ca. 1918-27 (Box 517, Folder 18)
        - "Industrial Problems," 1923, 1927 (Box 517, Folder 19)
        - Summer Session, 1926-27 (Box 517, Folder 20-21)
    - Oversize box
      - National Industrial Council Financial Ledger: receipts and expenditures of Industrial Clubs, 1947-49 (Box 518)
      - National Industrial Progress Day scrapbook, 1945 (Box 518)
  - Subseries B. Immigration and Foreign Communities
    - General and history
      - General, 1911-93, n.d. (Box 519, Folder 1-2)
      - Brochures and pamphlets, 1913-31, n.d. (Box 519, Folder 3)
      - "Foreign Community and Immigration Work of the National Young Women's Christian Association" by Edith Terry Bremer, 1916 (Box 519, Folder 4)
    - Department, Commissions, and Committees
      - Minutes
        - Special Committee of Research and Investigation (into the moral, physical, intellectual, and spiritual conditions of immigrant women): minutes and reports, 1910-11 (Box 519, Folder 5)
        - Committee on Immigration and Foreign Community Work/Immigration Sub-Committee, 1915-17, [see also War Work Council, Foreign-Born Women for Jul 1917-Mar 1920 in Series VII] (Box 519, Folder 6)
        - Committee on Foreign Born Women/Department of Work with Foreign-Born Women, May 1920-May 1924 (Box 519, Folder 7-8)
        - Immigration and Foreign Communities Department,, Oct 1924-30 (Box 519, Folder 9-11)
        - Staff meetings, 1926-31 (Box 519, Folder 12-13)
      - Commission on the Second Generation Girl/First Generation Americans (aka Commission II)
        - General, 1926-30, n.d. (Box 519, Folder 14)
        - Case studies, n.d. (Box 519, Folder 15-16)
        - Correspondence and memoranda, 1927-31 (Box 519, Folder 17)
        - Minutes, 1927-31 (Box 519, Folder 18)
        - Questionnaires
          - General, 1925-26, n.d. (Box 519, Folder 19)
          - Schedule on Family Relationships in Certain Nationality Groups, 1929, n.d. (Box 520, Folder 1)
        - Reports
          - Second Generation Study, Buffalo YWCA: minutes and reports, 1932-33 (Box 520, Folder 2)
          - Subcommittee on Second Generation Girls to the Planning Committee of the Brooklyn YWCA, 1936 (Box 520, Folder 3)